片名：小飛俠
The second star to the right
一閃一閃的星星星星
shines in the night for you
在黑夜中閃爍
to tell you that the dreams you plan
它彷彿在告訴你 在告訴你
really can come true
美夢會成真
the second star to the right
一閃一閃的星星星星
shines with a light so rare
它不停照耀著
and if it's neverland you need
它彷彿在告訴你 也在指引你
its light will lead you there
引你進入夢鄉
twinkle, twinkle little star
星星星星閃在夜空中
so we'll knowwhere you are
也彷彿在告訴你 在傾訴
gleaming in the skies above
星星星星閃在夜空中
lead us to the land we dream of
會把美夢變成真實
and when our journey is through
當美夢將要結束
each time we say good night
我們更要珍惜
we'll thankthe little star that shines
讓美夢永遠跟隨你
the second from the right
進入甜蜜夢鄉
all this has happened before,
這所有的一切以前曾經發生過
and it will all happen again.
而以後仍然會發生
But this time, it happened in London.
這一次是在倫敦
It happened on a quiet street in bloomsbury.
在布隆百瑞的一條安靜的街上
That corner house over there...
轉角的房子裡 住的是達林家族
Is the home of the Darling family.
彼得潘之所以選中了這棟房子
And Peter Pan chose this particular house...
是因為這裡住的人中
Because there were people here who believed in him.
有人相信他的存在
There was Mrs. Darling.
這位是達林太太
George, dear, do hurry.
喬治，快一點啊
We mustn't be late for the partyyou know.
你知道這個宴會 我們絕對不能遲到的
Mrs. Darling believed that Peter Pan...
達林太太相信彼得潘
Was the spirit of youth, but Mr. Darling
是屬於小時候的精靈,但是達林先生呢…
mary, unless I find my cuff links,
瑪莉，除非你找到我的袖扣
we don't go to the party.
否則我們就不去
And if we don't go to the party.
但假如我們不參加的話
I can never show my face in the office again.
我就永遠不用再到公司去了
And if I... Ouch!
假如我永遠不…哦!
Well, Mr. Darling was a practical man.
當然啦 達林先生是一個特殊人物
The boys, however, John and Michael,
無論如何 約翰和麥克都相信
believed Peter Pan was a real person,
彼得潘是真實的人
and made him the hero of all their nursery games.
而且是他們遊戲中的英雄
Blast you, Peter Pan.
去死吧，彼得潘
Give up, Captain Hook?
虎克船長，投降吧 休想!
Give up? I'll teach you to cut off me hand!
我來教你怎麼樣 砍掉我的右手
Oh, no, John.
約翰，不對
It was the left hand.
…是左手
Oh, yes. Thankyou, Wendy.
噢，對了 謝謝你啊，溫蒂
Wendy, the eldest, not only believed,
溫蒂，最大的孩子
but she was the supreme authority on Peter pan...
她不但相信有彼得潘
And all his marvelous adventures.
同時還是所有冒險事跡的 最高權威
Oh, Nana,
噢，娜娜，
must we always take that nastytonic?
我們一定要吃 這麼難吃的藥嗎？
Nana, the nursemaid, being a dog,
娜娜，是個保母 以一隻狗來說
kept her opinions to herself,
她的確盡忠職守守
and viewed the whole affair with a certain tolerance.
而且很能容忍所有的事情
Take that!
打死你…
I'll slash you to ribbons!
好大膽的人 看我把你給撕爛
I'll cut you to pieces!
我要把你砍成一段一段的
- aha! - ouch!
啊…哈!
Careful, Michael, my glasses.
小心，麥克，我的眼鏡
I'm sorry, John.
對不起，約翰
You'll never leave this ship alive! Oh, yes, I will.
我絕不會讓你活著下船的 哼，我一定會的
Take that!
接招，哼!
Scuttle me bones boy!
好啊!你打斷我的骨頭
I'll slit your gizzard.
我要撕裂你的肉
No, you won't. Back! Back!
哼!你才不行呢!
Back, villain!
退後…退後…你這個壞蛋
Insolent pup!
可惡的爛狗
Wicked pirate!
哼!可惡的海盜
I got you!
啊哈，我抓到你了
You didn't either. You never touched me.
才沒有，你永遠碰不到我
Take that, and that!
接招!接招! 刺到了
Ooh.,
孩子們…
boys, less noise, please.
孩子們… 不要吵啦
Hello, father. You old bilge rat!
喔，嗨，爸爸 你這個老傢伙…
What? Now see here, Michael.
什麼？ 麥克，你聽著
Not you, father. He's Peter Pan.
爸，他是說我啦 我們在玩，他是彼得潘
And John's Captain Hook.
我是虎克船長啊 噢!
Yes, of course. Have you seen my...
對…當然了,嗯…有沒有看見我的袖…噢…
Nana, for goodness sake!
娜娜…我的老天爺啊 你…
Where are those cuff links?
我的袖扣在哪裡啊？
Cuff links?
袖扣？爸爸？
Yes, the gold ones.
是啊…金的那副啊
The buried treasure, where is it?
麥克，我們的寶藏呢？ 在哪裡？
I don't know. The map.
我不知道啊 寶藏圖…
- where's the treasure map? - it got lost.
寶藏圖在哪裡啊？ 不見了
My shirt front!
天啊…我的領巾
You found it!
好棒喔，好棒喔!你找到了
Yes, so I have, and here after...
是啊!現在呢…
Don't paw me, Michael.
麥克，不要抓我
This is my last clean...
這是我最後一件乾淨的了
No-o-o!
噢!不，不!
George, dear, we really must hurry.
喬治，我們真的趕快一點了
Mary, look!
不然要遲到了 瑪莉…你看
George!
喬治
It's chalk.
只是粉筆嘛
Why, Michael. It's not his fault.
天啊，麥克.這又不是他的錯
It's in the story.
故事裡就是這樣的啊
Wendy says... Wendy? Story?
而且溫蒂說… 溫蒂？故事？
I might have known.
我就知道
Wendy!
溫蒂
Wendy! Yes, father?
溫蒂 爸，什麼事啊？
Would you kindly... Oh, mother!
溫蒂，你可不可以… 哇!媽
- you look lovely. - Thank you, dear.
你好漂亮喔 謝謝你，親愛的
Wendy.
其實這是件舊衣服了 溫蒂!
Just my old gown made over...
我把它整理一下 沒想到還能夠穿呢!
Mary, if you don't mind...
瑪莉啊，你能不能讓我…
Why, father,
啊!爸
what have you done to your shirt?
你看你把你領巾弄的啦!
What have I...?
我弄的？噢!
Oohhh!
哎…
Now George, really it comes right off.
喬治啊 何必對孩子們那麼大聲呢
That's no excuse. Wendy,
嫌我大聲？溫蒂啊
haven't I warned you?
我不是告訴過你嗎!
Stuffing the boys with silly stories...
不要老說一些古怪的故事 給你弟弟們聽的？
But theyaren't!
他們沒有怎麼樣啊
I saytheyare. Captain crook,
我就說有啊,虎克船長…
Peter pirate! Peter Pan, father.
彼得派…我…
Pan, pirate, poppycock!
彼得潘，爸爸
管他什麼潘啊派啊的 反正就是一些胡說
You don't understand.
可是…爸爸 你不會懂的
Absolute poppycock!
根本就是胡說八道
And let me tell you, this ridiculous...
好了好了 讓我來告訴你們好了
Now, George... "now, George"?
從現在開始啊 好了…喬治,好了…喬治
"now, George"?
好了…喬治
Well, now, George will have his say!
我告訴你們 喬治現在有自己的說法了
Please, dear.
拜託…親愛的 瑪莉
The child's growing up.
孩子們已經長大了
It's high time she had a room of her own.
應該有自己的房間了
- father! - George!
爸 喬治
- what? - no!
什麼？ 不要
I mean it. Young lady,
我決定了
this is your last night in the nursery,
小姐，今晚是你最後一夜 睡在這個房間裡了
and that's my last word... Yelp!
這也是我對這件事的 最後的決定
Uh, ah, oh!
Ooooh!
Ooh, ow!
No!
天啊…
No-o-o!
Ohhhh.
噢…
Poor Nana.
可憐的…可憐的娜娜
"poor Nana"?
可憐的娜娜？
This is the last straw!
這也是最後一次了
Out! Out, I say!
出去…給我滾出去…
No, father, no.
不要!爸爸，不要 就要!
There'll be no more dogs for nursemaids...In this house!
這個家裡 永遠不再用狗保母了
Goodbye, Nana.
再見，娜娜
"poor Nana."
可憐的娜娜
oh, yes. "poor Nana."
but "poor father"? Oh, no.
居然不是可憐的爸爸
哼!等著瞧好了!
Blast it! Where is that rope?
繩子跑哪去了？嗯!
Oh, thankyou.
噢，謝謝
Don't lookat me like that.
不要這樣嘛…娜娜 不要用這種眼光看我嘛
It's nothing personal.
絕對與你無關的
It's just that...
只不過是…
You're not reallya nurse at all.
因為你並不是真正的保母啊
You're, well, a dog.
你呢，只是一隻狗
And the children aren't puppies,
而他們也不是小狗
they're people.
他們是孩子啊
And sooner or later,
而且早晚要長大的啊
people have to grow up.
人總是要長大的嘛
But mother, I don't want to grow up.
可是媽，我不想長大
Now dear,
好了，乖，
don't worryabout it anymore tonight.
今天晚上 就不必再管這件事情了
He called Peter Pan "absolute poppycock."
他居然說彼得潘根本就是假的
I'm sure he didn't mean it, John.
約翰，我相信他 一定不是有意的
Father was just upset.
你們的父親 只不過有一點生氣罷了
Poor Nana,
可憐的娜娜
out there all alone.
一個人在外面
No more tears, Michael.
麥克，不要再哭了
It's a warm night. She'll be all right.
今天並不冷啊,她在外面沒有關係的
Mother.
媽媽
What, dear?
什麼事？小乖乖
The buried treasure.
那個寶藏…
Now children,
孩子們
don't judge your father too harshly.
不要再批評你們的父親了
After all,
不管怎麼說
he really loves you very much.
他還是非常疼愛你們的
Don't lock it mother. He might come back.
媽，不要鎖上 他也許會回來的
He?
他？
Yes, Peter Pan.
對啊，彼得潘
You see, I found something that belongs to him.
因為我撿到了一個 屬於他的東西
- and what's that? - his shadow.
喔，什麼東西啊？ 他的影子
Shadow?
影子？
Nana had it,
嗯，是娜娜找到的
but I took it away.
我… 我把它收起來了
Oh?
哦，
Yes, of course.
好了
Good night, dear.
快睡吧，晚安
George do you thinkthe children will be safe without Nana?
喬治啊，你認為把娜娜 關在外面，孩子們安全嗎？
Safe of course safe. Why not?
安全？當然安全 為什麼不安全呢？
Well, Wendy said something about a shadow.
哦，因為溫蒂她說什麼影子…
Shadow? Whose shadow? Peter Pan's.
影子？誰的影子啊？ 彼得潘的啊
Oh, Peter Pan's. Peter Pan's!
喔，彼得潘的 彼得潘
You don't say.
不要再說了，
Goodness gracious, whatever shall we do?
我的天啊 你們到底有完沒完啊？
Sound the alarm!
還有… 不要再說了
Call scotland yard! There must have been someone.
我要打電話給蘇格蘭警場
Mary, of all the impossible childish fiddle-faddle!
瑪莉啊，彼得潘只不過是 孩子們的童話而已
Peter Pan, indeed!
彼得潘確實是存在的
How can we expect the children to grow up and be practical...
孩子們什麼時候 才能長大啊
When you're as bad as theyare?
當年你還不是一樣嗎？
No wonder Wendy gets these idiotic ideas.
難怪溫蒂…
Over there, tink,
小叮噹，就是這裡
in its den.
在櫃子裡
Is it there?
有沒有啊？
Must be here somewhere.
應該在這附近的啊
Tink!
小叮噹，
Shhh!
噓…
Stop playing.
不要鬧了啦
Help me find my shadow.
快點幫我找影子嘛
Shadow,
影子
oh, shadow.
嗚呼，影子…
Ting-a-ling.
Huh?
Aha!
啊哈!
Peter Pan!
哦…彼得潘!
I knewyou'd come back.
哈…彼得，我就知道你會回來的
I saved your shadow for you.
我幫你把你的影子收好了
I do hope it isn't rumpled.
喔，我希望我沒有弄壞了它
You look exactlythe way I thought you would.
對了!你看起來 跟我想像的一模一樣哎
Taller, perhaps...
也許…也許要高一點
You can't stick it on with soap.
你不可能 用肥皂把它黏起來的
It needs sewing.
它是要用針縫才行
That's the proper wayto do it.
用針縫的話 它就再也跑不掉了啊
I've never sewn shadows before.
可是，我以前也不知道耶
Sorry shadow I mean.
喔，我是說把影子縫起來
Of course,
我一眼看見它
I knew it was yours.
就知道是你的影子
I said to myself,
然後，我就告訴自己
"put it away for him until he comes back."
一定要把你的影子收好 等你回來
oh, sure come back.
沒錯吧，你真的回來了 對不對？
And you did, didn't you, Peter?
你回來拿了 對不對？彼得？
One can't leave his shadow lying about...
沒有人能夠把自己的影子丟了
And not miss it, sooner or later.
而不找回來的
Don't you agree?
對不對？
What I still don't understand...
但是有一件事我不明白
Is how Nana got it.
娜娜怎麼會找到 你的影子的啊？好奇怪哦
Sit down. It won't take long.
她又不是… 你坐下，不會太久的
She isn't vicious.
娜娜又不是精靈啊
She's a wonderful nurse...
她只是一個好保母耶
Girls talktoo much.
雖然爸爸說她是… 女孩子的話可真多耶
Yes, girls talk...
嗯…對 女孩子的話可真…多
Hmm? Oh.
Get on with it, girl.
好了，快弄吧，女孩
My name is Wendy, Wendy moria, and...
我叫溫蒂，溫蒂摩爾
Wendy's enough. Oh.
我今年只有… 夠了，溫蒂
How did Nana get your shadow, Peter?
可是娜娜怎麼找到 你影子的啊？彼得
She jumped at me at the window.
那天晚上 她在窗前向我撲過來
What were you doing there?
你在那裡做什麼？
I came to listen to the stories.
我在那裡聽故事啊
But my stories are all about you.
聽故事？ 我說的都是你的故事啊!
Of course
是啊，
that's way I like them.
所以我才喜歡聽啊
I tell 'em to the lost boys.
我還說給那些 走失的小孩聽呢
The lost... I remember.
走失的小孩？ 喔，我想起來了
They're your men.
他們是你的手下 啊…嗯
I'm so glad you came backtonight.
我好高興喔 你今天晚上能來
I might never have seen you. Why
否則我就見不到你了 為什麼？
because I have to grow up tomorrow. Grow up?
因為我明天就要長大了 長大!
Tonight's my last night in the nursery.
再也不能睡在這個房間裡
But that means no more stories.
這麼說，我再也聽不到故事了
Mm-hmm. No!
I won't have it. Come on!
不，我不答應 跟我來!
But where are we going?
可…可是我們要去哪兒呀？
To neverland.
去我的夢幻島
Neverland!
夢幻島？
You'll never grow up there.
在那裡你永遠不會長大
Oh, Peter,
哇，彼得
it will be so wonderful!
那真是太棒了耶
But wait!
哎，等一等，等一等
What would mother say?
我媽媽會怎麼樣呢？
Mother? What's "mother"? Why, Peter,
媽媽？什麼是媽媽？
a mother's someone who loves you...
媽媽…媽媽是一個…永遠愛你關心你，還有…
And tells you stories...
她是一個會說故事給你聽的人
Good!
好
You can be our mother.
你可以做我們的媽媽! 快走吧
Just a minute.
等一等嘛，讓我想想…
I have to pack,
我必須要先…
and I must leave a note.
我還先留個條子說我會回來
I couldn't stay too long...
當然囉，我不能待太久
Oh, neverland.
還有… 噢…夢幻島
I'm so happy,
我好高興啊
I think I'll give you a kiss.
我好想要給你…一個吻
What's a "kiss"?
什麼是…一個吻？
Well,
喔，
I'll show you. Ouch!
那是…我做給你看
Stop it, tink!
哎，住手 住手，小叮噹
John! John, he's here!
約翰，起來，起來 他在這裡耶
Huh?
喔…我的媽呀
Jiminy!
What in the world was that?
誰在抓我的頭髮？
Tinkerbell. I don't knowwhat got into her. Hello, Peter Pan.
是小叮噹 我也不知道她怎麼了
I'm Michael.
嗨，彼得潘，我是麥克
My name is John.
我的名字叫約翰，你好嗎？
How do you do? Oh, look!
嗨，你好 哇，你看，
A firefly!
螢火蟲耶
A pixie!
一個小精靈
Amazing.
天啊!
What's she doing? Talking.
小精靈在幹什麼啊？ 說話啊
What did she say?
她說什麼啊？
She says you're a big ugly girl!
她說你是一個 又大又醜的女孩
Ha, ha, ha. Oh.
Well, I think she's lovely.
可是…我認為她很可愛
Come on Wendy, let's go.
好了，來吧，溫蒂 我們走囉
Where are we going? To neverland.
我們去哪裡啊？
Neverland?
去夢幻島 夢幻島？
Peter's taking us. Us?
彼得帶我們去 我們？
Of course, I couldn't go without Michael and John.
我不可能不帶 約翰和麥克一起去的
I should like to cross swords...
哦，我會非常高興能去看看
With some real buccaneers.
真正的海盜戰爭的
And fight pirates, too.
對，還要去打海盜
Well, all right, but you gotta take orders.
呵…好吧 不過你們都要服從命令喔
Aye, aye, sir.
是的，長官
Me, too.
我也是
But Peter, how do we get to neverland?
彼得，我們怎麼去呢？
Fly, of course.
當然用飛的囉
Fly?
飛？
It's easy.
那很容易嘛
All you have to do is to...
你們只要、你們只要…
Is to...
只要…
Ha, that's funny.
哼，真滑稽
What's matter?
怎麼回事啊？
Don't you know?
你不知道嗎？
Oh, sure.
怎麼會呢？
It's just that I never thought about it before.
只不過我以前從來沒有想過呢
Saythat's it!
對，就這麼辦
You think of a wonderful thought.
你們想一件很棒的事情
Any happy little thought?
隨便什麼事嗎？
Uh-huh.
唔
- like toys at christmas? - sleigh bells, snow?
比方說耶誕節的玩具？ 耶誕節？下雪？
Yep.
對!
Watch me, now. Here I go!
看著我，我要飛了
It's easier than pie.
很容易吧!
- he can fly! - he can fly!
他會飛哎! 他會飛哎
He flewed!
飛了
Now, you try.
你們也試試看
I'll think of a mermaid lagoon...
我來想一個在神奇月光下的
Underneath a magic moon.
美人魚珊瑚礁
I'll think I'm in a pirate's cave.
我來想像在一個海盜洞裡
I'll be an injun brave.
我要想我是一個超人
Now, everybodytry.
我們一起來試試看
One, two, three!
一…二…三…
We can fly, we can fly!
哇…我們會飛了
We can fly-y-y-y!
我們會飛了!啊…
This won't do.
這樣不對，
What's the matter with you?
怎麼會摔跤呢？
All it takes is faith and trust.
你們一定要有自信心才行啊!
Oh,
噢!我忘了一樣東西
dust!
金粉
Dust?
金粉？ 金粉？
Yep!
對了
Just a little bit of pixie dust.
只要一點點…神奇的金粉
Now, think of the happiest things.
好了!現在想一點快樂的事情
It's the same as having wings.
這樣就像長了翅膀一樣
Let's try it once more.
讓我們再來試一遍
Look, we're rising off the floor!
看，我們從地板上升起來了
Jiminy!
好棒啊
Oh, my. We can fly!
天啊，我們會飛了
You can fly!
你們會飛了
We can fly!
我們會飛了
Come on!
來吧，
Here we go-o-o!
各位 準備出發囉
Off to neverland!
向夢幻島前進
Think of a wonderful thought
願我去尋找夢想
any merry little thought
一個美麗的夢想
think of christmas, think of snow
像朵白雲空中飄
think of sleigh bells, off you go
也像雪花飛啊飛
like reindeer in the sky
來吧，跟我去飛…
arf, arf!
飛啊飛
You can flyyou can fly
飛啊飛，
you can fly
飛啊飛…
think of the happiest things
我願像小鳥一樣
it's the same as having wings
自由自在的飛翔
thinka path that moonbeams make
讓那月亮伴著我
if the moon is still awake
伴我飛到天際邊
you'll see him wink his eye
盡情瘋狂去飛
you can fly, you can fly
飛啊飛，飛啊飛
arf, arf! You can fly
飛啊飛… 飛啊飛…
up you go with a heigh and ho
飛翔在天空中
to the stars beyond the moon
感覺沒有話可以形容
there's a neverland waiting for you
它會帶你到神秘地方
where all your happy dreams come true
把煩惱忘掉盡情飛
every dream that you dream will come true
它會讓你的夢變成真
come on, Nana!
快點，娜娜
When there's a smile in your heart
置身在天空之中
there's no better time to start
身邊只有雲和風
think of all the joyyou'll find
把世界拋在腦後
when you leave the world behind
沒有話可以形容
and bid your cares goodbye
只要你和我去飛
you can fly, you can fly
飛啊飛，盡情飛
you can fly
飛啊飛…
there it is!
就在那裡，溫蒂
Second star to the right...
右邊那顆星星星星的光芒
And straight on 'til morning.
會一直閃爍到天明
When there's a smile in your heart
享受在天空之中
there's no better time to start
沒有話可以形容
think of all the joyyou'll find
把世界拋在腦後
when you leave the world behind
讓煩惱一掃而空
and bid your cares goodbye
只要你和我去飛
you can fly, you can fly
飛啊飛，盡情飛
飛啊飛，盡情飛… 盡情飛…
oh, a pirate's life is a wonderful life
哦…海盜的生活真多姿多彩
a rovin' over the sea
馳騁在浩瀚大海
give me a career as a buccaneer
在海上時蕩來蕩去
it's the life of a pirate for me
這生活過的既輕鬆又自由自在
oh, the life of a pirate for me
哦…海盜生活實在過癮
oh, a pirate's life is a wonderful life
哦…海盜的生活真多姿多彩
they never buryyour bones
什麼也都不用疑猜
for when it's all over a jolly sea rover
日子這樣蕩來蕩去
drops in on his friend, davy jones
這生活得既輕鬆又自由自在
oh, my good friend, davy jones
哦…既輕鬆又自由自在 自由自在
good morning, shipmates!
早安，各位
What's good about it, Mr. Smee?
早？早你個頭啊，史密先生
Here we are,
我們在這個爛小島上
collecting barnacles on this miserable island.
玩一些無聊的遊戲
While his nibs plays ring-around-the-rosy...
而他卻把大好的時光
With Peter Pan.
用來計劃抓彼得潘
We ought to be attending to the business...
小心，小心走火啊
Of looting ships.
我們應該計劃搶船才對
I've almost forgotten...
現在我都忘了
Howto slit a throat.
該怎麼樣割人的喉嚨了
Better hop it, and tell the captain...
乾脆告訴船長
We wants to put to sea!
我們…要…出…海 怎麼樣？
See?
哈哈，你看他那副德行 就是啊!哈哈…
Blast that Peter Pan!
保佑那個彼得潘吧
If I could only find his hideout,
只要我能找到他藏身的地方
I'd trap him in his lair.
我就一定能夠抓到他
But where is it?
可是在哪裡呢？
Mermaid lagoon?
美人魚珊瑚礁？
No, we've searched that.
不對，我已經找過了
We've combed cannibal cove.
我們也找過食人獸的洞穴
Here?
這裡？
No, no, no!
不對，不對
That's Indian territory...
那是印地安人的地方
But wait.
不過…
Those redskins knowthis island...
那些印地安人 比我熟悉我的船
Better than I do me own ship.
還要瞭解這個小島
Ah...
I wonder.
我猜想…
Good morning, captain.
早安，船長
I've got it!
我知道了
Tiger lily, Smee!
莉莉公主，史密
Tiger lily, captain?
莉莉公主啊？船長
The chief's daughter.
酋長的女兒
She'll knowwhere pan is hiding.
她會知道彼得潘在哪裡
But-but-but, will she talk,captain?
可…可… 可是她會說嗎？船長
A little persuasion...
哦… 給她一點壓力也許就會了
Might be in order.
比方說
Now, let me see.
讓我想想
Boiling in oil?
上刀山下油鍋
Keelhauling?
丟到海裡，
Marooning?
藏起來
Oh, a pirate's life is a wonderful life
哦…海盜的生活真多姿多彩
you'll find adventure and sport
充滿著緊張又好玩
but live every minute
你可沒有想到
for all that is in it
生命這麼短暫
the life of a pirate is sho-oo-rt
快樂的日子也很短暫…
Now let me see. Where was I?
我剛剛說到哪兒啦？
Oh, dear, cap'n hook.
喔，親愛的虎克船長
Shooting a man in the middle of his cadenza,
當一個人開心唱歌的時候
it ain't good form.
你殺他那是不好的行為耶
Good form, Mr. Smee?
不好的行為？史密先生？
Blast good form!
你在說什麼呀？
Did pan show good form when he did this to me?
那個彼得潘這樣對我 那就是好的行為了嗎？
Why, cap'n,
可是…船長啊
cutting your hand off was a childish prank.
他只是小孩子惡作劇不小心砍斷了你的手啊
Aye, but throwing it to the crocodile!
對!然後把我的手 丟去餵鱷魚
That cursed beast liked the taste of me so well,
然後那個混蛋東西 非常喜歡我的肉
he's followed me ever since,
不管我走到哪裡 它都緊追不捨
licking his chops for the rest of me.
隨時等著吃剩下的我
He'd of had you by now...
嗯…假如它 沒有吞下那只滴答鍾啊
If he hadn't swallowed that alarm clock.
它早就吃下你了
But nowwhen he's about,
現在只要它在你附近
he warns you, as you might say,
就可以用滴答聲警告你啊
with his tick-tock, tick-tock.
像滴答，滴答，滴答…
Smee-e-e-e!
救命啊，史密
Please don't let him get me!
千萬不要讓它抓到我，史密
Don't let him get me!
不要讓它吃掉我，史密
Shame on you, upsetting the poor cap'n.
聽著!讓可憐的船長這麼害怕 你羞不羞啊？
There'll be no handouts today!
今天沒有手吃了
Shoo!
咻，咻…
Off with you!
走啦，走啦，
Go away! Out of here!
走啦 我說走開啦，走開啦
Is he gone, Smee?
它走了嗎？史密
Cap'n, all clear.
船長，不要擔心
Nothing to worry about.
沒事了，沒事了
Oh, Smee,
史密，史密
I can't stand it any longer.
我再也受不了了 我告訴你，我真的受不了了…
Now, now, captain. Just relax.
好了，船長 放輕鬆些
What you need is a shave;
你現在需要
A nice, soothing shave.
好好的修個臉
There, now.
舒舒服服的
Oh, a pirate's life is a wonderful life
海盜的生活真多彩多姿
a sailing over the sea
馳騁在浩瀚大海
give me a career as a buccaneer.
只要工作輕輕鬆…
I can't help noticing.
哎，船長啊! 假如你不能再做一個
You just ain't been your usual jolly self of late.
平凡快樂的海盜的話 我也沒辦法再幫你了
Give me a career as a buccaneer
我只要求輕輕鬆的工作
the crew's getting a might uneasy, cap'n.
而且船長啊 船員們已經有點兒不耐煩了
That is, what's left of it.
好了，只剩下這一點點了
Now, why don't we put to sea,
我看乾脆我們出海吧
leave neverland, and forget Peter Pan?
別再管什麼彼得潘了 好不好啊？
There, now.
行了
Squawk!
We'd all be happier,
假如我們不再這樣
not to mention a lot healthier.
我們會快樂得多了
Oh!
Cap'n! Oh, dear!
船長？噢，天啊!
I've never shaved him this close before.
我刮臉從來沒有 把頭刮不見了
Oh, oh-oh-oh!
Don't worry, it must be somewhere about.
嗯…別害怕，船長 我一定幫你把頭找回來啊
Get up, you idiot!
放我下來，你這個白癡
Aye, aye, sir.
啊…是，船長
I found it, cap'n!
噢，我找到了，船長
Good as new.
完整無缺啊
You blithering...!
沒見過你這種笨蛋
Peter Pan ahoy!
彼得潘出現了
Where away?
什麼？在哪裡啊？
Three points off the starboard bow!
在右舷三點鐘方向
Swoggle me eyes, it is pan...
真不敢相信，真是彼得潘啊
Headed this waywith more of those scurvy brats!
還帶了幾個小鬼 朝這兒飛過來了
Mr. Smee, pipe up the crew.
史密先生，快召集船員
Aye, aye, sir. Pipe up the crew.
啊…是的，船長 召集船員
All hands on deck!
全體集合
所有人員到甲板上
Lookalive, you swabs!
準備槍炮
We've got him this time.
史密，這一次 我一定會抓到他的
That we have.
一定會的，船長
Man the long tom, you bilge rats!
全體就戰鬥位置
I've waited years for this.
我可是等了好多年了
That's not counting the holidays.
這算什麼 以前的帳還沒算呢!
Double the powder and shorten the fuse!
加強火力，瞄準目標 加強火力，瞄準目標
A pretty sight. We'll pot 'em...
好美的景觀啊，史密
Like sitting ducks.
就像待宰的羔羊
All right, men!
各位，瞄準了…
Range 42! Range 42.
仰角42度 仰角42度
Elevation 65! Elevation 65.
高度65度 高度65度
3 degrees west! 3 degrees west.
往西3度 往西3度
Steady now!
準備發射
Steady!
準備… 準備!
Oh Peter, it's just as I've always dreamed it would be.
哇!彼得 真的跟夢裡的情形一樣耶
Look, John,
噢，約翰你看
there's mermaid lagoon!
那是美人魚珊瑚礁耶
By jove!
真的 你看，
And the Indian encampment!
還有印地安人的帳蓬呢
Look,
哇，你們看
there's cap'n hookand the pirates!
是虎克船長和他的海盜耶
Look out!
小心!
Take Wendyand the boys to the island.
小叮噹 快帶溫蒂他們到島上
I'll stay here for a while.And draw hook's fire.
我留在這兒對付虎克
Hook, you codfish!
嘿!虎克，你這個膽小鬼
Here!
我在這裡
Tinkerbell!
小叮噹…
Not so fast! Please, Tinkerbell.
不要那麼快，小叮噹
We can't keep up with you!
我們趕不上你啊
Tinkerbell, wait!
小叮噹，慢一點 慢一點!
Ouch!
啊!
So-o-o!
好啊!
Who ya shoving? You, that's who.
幹嘛推我？幹嘛推我？
打我頭 我就打你頭
怎麼樣？我打你…
Ting-a-ling.
打死你…
Orders from pan?
啊，彼得的命令？
Hold it, men!
安靜 小叮噹，
- what's the orders?
是什麼命令啊？
A terrible what?
一個討厭的什麼？ 叫溫蒂的鳥
- Wendy bird. - Wendy bird?
溫蒂的鳥？
Flying this way?
向這邊飛來？
Pan's orders are... What?
彼得的命令是？…什麼？
- smash it? - kick it?
打死它？ 踢它？
Ting-a-ling.
在它身上跳？
Oh, shoot it down!
哦，把它射下來 把它射下來…
Yeah, yeah!
快走，
Yeah, come on!
我們走囉
- I see it! - me, too.
我看見了 我也是，我也看到了
Ready...
準備… 瞄準…
Aim...
Fire!
發射…
打死它、打死它
Oh, Peter,
噢，彼得
you saved my life.
謝謝你救了我的命
Are you hurted, Wendy? No, Michael.
你有沒有受傷？溫蒂
Good heavens, Wendy, you might have been killed.
我的天啊，溫蒂 你差一點就沒命了
Hey, pan,
嘿!彼得
I got it with my skull buster!
是我打的…嘿…彼得 她是被我的箭射中的
Did not, we did!
你胡說，是我射中的 是我，
I did!
是我
是我打的 是我打中的…
Attention!
安靜!
I'm certainly proud of you.
哈…你們可真了不起啊
Blockheads! I bring you a mother...
笨蛋!
To tell you stories...
我找了一個媽媽來 說故事給你們聽
A mother?
媽媽？
And you shoot her down.
而你們卻把她打下來 可是…小叮噹說它是鳥啊
Well, tink said it was a bird.
Tink said what?
小叮噹說什麼？
She said you said to shoot it down.
她說是你說要我們 把她打下來的
Tinkerbell?
小叮噹，小叮噹!
Come here.
過來
You're charged with high treason, tink.
你犯了叛國的大罪
Are you guilty or not guilty?
你認不認罪？
Guilty?
認了？
Don't you know...
難道你不知道
You might have killed her?
會把她殺死嗎？
Tinkerbell,
小叮噹
I hereby banish you forever.
我判你被永遠驅逐出境
Please, not forever.
拜託…不要永遠嘛!
For a week, then.
好吧，那就一個星星期
Come on Wendy, I'll showyou the island.
來吧，溫蒂，我帶你參觀一下
Oh, Peter, the mermaids?
噢，彼得，美人魚
Let's go hunting.
不要，我們去打獵啦 老虎嗎？
Tigers? Nah, bears.
不是，是熊
I should prefer to see the aborigines.
我希望能去看土人 長得是什麼樣子
And the Indians.
還有印地安人喔
All right, go capture a few Indians.
那好吧!你們就去 抓幾個印地安人吧
John, you be the leader.
約翰，你當隊長
I shall tryto be worthy of my post.
放心，我一定會做個好隊長的
Forward, march!
現在，出發
Come on, bear.
走吧，熊熊
Oh Michael do be careful.
哎，麥克，一定要小心啊
Come on Wendy, I'll showyou the mermaids.
來啊，溫蒂 我帶你去看美人魚
Following the leader
趕快跟著我走
the leader, the leader
跟我走，跟我走
we're following the leader wherever he may go
來趕快跟著我走 不管往哪裡走
tee-dum, tee-dee
叮咚，叮叮
a teedle ee-do tee-day
叮咚叮咚叮叮
tee-dum, tee-dee
叮咚，叮叮
it's part of the game we play
這是我們的遊戲
tee-dum, tee-dee
叮咚，叮叮
the words are easy to say
這是我們的口號
just a teedle ee-dum, a teedle ee-do tee-day
向前，叮咚叮咚 叮咚叮咚叮叮
tee-dum, tee-dee
叮咚，叮叮
a teedle ee-do tee-dum
叮咚叮咚叮叮
we're one for all
我們一起去
and all of us out for fun
尋找新的遊戲
we march in line, and followthe other one
我們齊步算準一個節拍
with a teedle ee-do a teedle ee-di tee-dum
向前，叮咚叮咚 叮咚叮咚叮叮
following the leader
趕快跟著我走
the leader, the leader
跟我走，跟我走
we're following the leader wherever he may go
來趕快跟著我走 不管往哪裡走
we're out to fight the injuns
要齊步勇敢殺敵
the injuns, the injuns
不要怕不退縮
we're out to fight the injuns
要齊步勇敢殺敵
because he told us so
直到最後勝利
tee-dum, tee-dee
叮咚，叮叮
a teedle ee-do tee-day
叮咚叮咚叮叮
we march along
我們一起
and these are the words we say
不需要再說逃避
tee-dum, tee-dee, a teedle dee deedle dee-ay
叮咚，叮叮 叮咚叮咚叮叮
oh, a teedle dee-dum, a teedle dee-do tee-day
喔，叮咚叮咚 叮咚叮咚叮叮
oh, a teedle dee-dum, a teedle dee-do tee-day.
Indians!
印地安人!
Blackfoot tribe!
嗯…黑腳部落的蹤跡
It belongs to the algonquin group.
屬於艾根肯族的
Quite savage.
是非常野蠻的噢
Let's go get 'em!
我們去抓他…
Gentlemen, we must plan our strategy.
各位，各位，首先我們要先研究一下戰略 什麼是戰略啊？
What's "stragedy"?
首先我們要先研究一下戰略 什麼是戰略啊？
A plan of attack. The initial phase...
進攻計劃啊，第一步，我們先這樣
Is an encircling maneuver.
把他們包圍起來
John, Indians!
約翰 印地安人，印地安人
Let me in!
讓我進去嘛
Remember,
你們聽著
the Indian is cunning, but not intelligent.
印地安人雖然很狡猾，可是並不聰明
We simply surround them, and take them by surprise...
所以… 我們只要把他們包圍起來，然後趁其不備的抓住他們
I'm terribly sorry, old chaps.
我真的很抱歉，
It's all my fault.
各位 都是我的錯
That's all right, wildcat.
噢，沒有關係啦，野貓
We don't mind.
喔，我們不會介意
We are ok.
不會介意的啦 不會介意
How.
好!
Hi, chief.
嗨，酋長 嗨，酋長，你好
For many moons,
長久以來
red man fight paleface lost boys.
紅人喜歡抓白人的小孩
Sometime, you win,
噢!噢!有時候是你們贏
sometime, we win.
有時候是我們贏
You win this time.
好吧，酋長，這次你贏了
Nowturn us loose.
可以放我們走了嗎？
Turn us loose? This is onlya game?
放了我們？ 你是說這只是一個遊戲？
When we win, we turn them loose.
是啊，如果我們贏了 也會放他們走
When theywin, theyturn us loose.
他們贏了，就放我們走 放我們走
This time, no turn 'em loose.
這一次不能放你們走啦
The chief's a great spoofer.
啊？哈…酋長最會騙人了
Me no spoof 'em!
酋長沒有騙人
Where you hide princess tiger lily?
你們把莉莉公主藏在哪裡？
Tiger lily?
哦…莉莉公主？
We ain't got her!
我們沒有抓你的莉莉公主
I've never seen her.
我從來沒有見過她啊
Me neither.
我也沒有，我們真的沒有 真的沒有
Heap big lie.
都在說謊
If tiger lily...
假如她在
Not back by sunset,
日落前沒有回來
burn 'em at stake.
把他們全部燒死
Just imagine,
真想不到，
real live mermaids.
活的美人魚耶
Would you like to meet them? I'd love to !
你想認識她們嗎？ 噢，彼得，我非常願意
All right, come on!
那就來吧
It's Peter!
是彼得耶
Hello, Peter!
嗨!彼得
Hello, girls!
嗨!你們好
I'm so glad to see you.
喔…我們好高興能見到你喔
Why did you stayaway so long?
你為什麼好久都不來了？
Did you miss me?
你想不想我們啊？
Tell us an adventure.
說你的故事給我們聽吧 要刺激一點的喔
Howabout the time I cut off hook's hand...
你們要不要聽我把虎克船長的手
And threw it to the crocodile.
砍下來喂鱷魚的故事啊？
I've always liked that one.
我最喜歡聽這一段了
Me, too.
我也是
I was on a rock...
那次我被四十多個人 包圍在一塊大石頭上面
Oh, Peter!
喂!彼得，她是誰啊？ 不對!好像是五十多個人
Who's she?
她是誰
Huh? Her?
嗯，她？
That's Wendy.
噢，她是溫蒂
What is she doing here?
一個女孩 她來做什麼？
And in her nightdress, too.
她居然還穿著睡衣呢
Come on, join us for a swim!
來吧!來跟我們一起游泳啊
I'm not dressed for it!
下來啊 我沒有穿泳衣啊
- please. - we insist!
不要拉，不要推我嘛! 來嘛
Peter!
彼得 哈…
快點啊，你下來嘛，你快下來啊
If you dare to come in me...
你們敢再靠近我試試看 溫蒂…
Wendy!
溫蒂
Theywere just having fun.
她們只是在跟你開玩笑嘛
Weren't you?
對不對啊，各位？
That's all.
就是啊
We were onlytrying to drown her.
我們不過想淹死她而已啊
You see?
你看吧
If you think for one minute...
如果你認為她們想要淹死我 是開玩笑的話，那…
Shhh, Wendy.
噓!溫蒂，不要說話
Yup, it's hook.
沒錯，是虎克
Hook!
虎克？ 虎克!
Quick, Wendy!
啊!快，溫蒂
They've captured tiger lily.
他們抓住了莉莉公主
Looks like they're heading for skull rock.
看來他們是要去骷髏石
Come on, Wendy.
來，溫蒂
Let's see what they're up to.
我們去看看他們想做什麼？
Now, me dear princess,
親愛的莉莉公主
this is me proposition.
你不想死在這個地方吧？
You tell me the hiding place of Peter Pan,
只要你肯告訴我 彼得潘藏身的地方啊
and I shall set you free.
我馬上放你自由
You dog! Poor tiger lily.
大壞蛋 可憐的莉莉公主
Am I not a man of me word, Mr. Smee?
我這個人最講信用了 史密，對不對啊？
Yes,
哦…對對，
always, cap'n.
偶爾會的啦!
You'd better talk, me dear.
親愛的，你最好快點說吧
Soon the tide will be in.
否則等一下漲潮,那可就太遲了
I'll showthe old codfish.
我要教訓一下那個壞蛋
Stay here, Wendy, and watch the fun.
溫蒂，你等著看好戲吧 嗯？
Remember,
聽清楚
there is no path through water...
在水底可不像在陸地
To the happy hunting ground.
是沒有地方可以逃的哦!
This is your last chance, tiger lily!
這是你最後的機會了 莉莉公主
Manatoa, great spirit of mighty seawater, speak.
我是偉大的海神夢阿圖
Beware, Captain Hook!
注意，虎克船長
Beware!
注意!
Did you hear that?
你聽到了嗎？
It's an evil spirit.
史密 是魔鬼哎，船長
Stand by, while I take a lookaround.
你小心看著 我到周圍去看看
Spirit of the great seawater, is it?
偉大的海神夢阿圖？哼!
Pssst, Wendy.
溫蒂，
Watch this.
你看喔
Mr. Smee?
史密先生
Yes, cap'n?
啊…船長？
Release the princess and take her back...
我要你放了公主 並且把她送回到
To her people.
她的村子去
Aye, aye, sir.
嗯…是，船長 放了公主
Release the prince... But?
嗯…可是，船長
But cap'n? Those are the orders, Mr. Smee!
這是命令，聽見了沒有？
Aye, aye, sir.
啊…是，船長
At last, cap'n hook's comin' to his senses.
虎克船長終於恢復理智了
That's odd!
我的天啊!
I told him the Indians wouldn't betray Peter Pan.
我早就告訴過他 印地安人不會出賣彼得潘的
Just what do you thinkyou are doing,
，能不能告訴我 你究竟在幹什麼呀？
Mr. Smee?
史密先生
Just what you told me, cap'n,
送她回去啊!
carrying out your orders.
這不是你的命令嗎？
My orders?
我的命令？
Why, yes, cap'n. Didn't you just say...
嗯…是啊，船長 你剛才你不是說放了她嗎？
Put her back,
你老糊塗了
you blithering idiot!
還不趕快去把她綁好!
My orders!
我的命令，
Of all the bumbling..
簡直胡說八道.
Mr. Smee,
史密先生
just exactlywhat do you thinkyou are doing?
你能不能夠告訴我 你究竟在幹什麼呀？
Putting her back, like I said.
照你說的在綁好啊，船長
I said nothing of the sort.
我什麼時候說過 你這個老糊塗
But, c-c-cap'n, d-d-didn't...
嗯…可…是，船長 你…不是說…
For the last time, Mr. Smee,
我再說一次，史密
take the princess backto her people!
放了公主並且把她 送回到她的村子去
Understand?
聽見了沒有？ 聽見了沒有…
Aye, aye, sir.
是，船長
One more thing.
噢，還有一件事情
When you return to the ship,
當你回到船上的時候呢
tell the crewto help themselves...
告訴全體的船員
To me best rum.
可以喝我最好的酒
Peter!
彼得!
Here's your spirit, Smee!
魔鬼在這裡，史密
Why, it's Peter Pan.
嗯…原來是彼得潘
Oh.
Scurvy brat!
卑鄙的傢伙
Thankyou, captain.
謝了，船長
Come down boy.
下來，小子
If you've a taste for cold steel.
我看你 敢不敢嘗鐵鉤子的滋味
Watch this, Wendy.
溫蒂，仔細看囉!
Oh Peter, do be careful.
彼得，你要小心哪!
Tryyour luck, Mr. Smee?
要不要試試運氣啊？
Let him have it!
打死他，射啊!
Come on, you idiot, blast him!
你這個大混蛋 給我打死他啊
Right here, Mr. Smee.
在這裡，史密先生
Hold it, you fool!
不要亂來啊!
No. No!
不要，不要
Cap'n?
船長
Oh, how dreadful.
噢，好可怕啊
What a pity, Mr. Smee.
真可惜啊，史密先生
I'm afraid we've lost the dear captain.
我想我們要失去 親愛的虎克船長了
Cap'n?
哎，船長
In the back, captain?
想偷襲啊，船長
Give it to him, cap'n.
打垮他，船長
Cleave him to the brisket.
把他撕成兩半
I've got you this time, pan.
這回你跑不掉了吧？
No!
呀…
Well, well, a codfish on a hook.
唉呀，可憐的膽小鬼 可憐喲!
I'll get you for this, pan,
就算是我拼了這條老命
if it's the last thing I do.
我一定要抓到你
I say, captain, do you hear something?
親愛的船長 有沒有聽到什麼聲音啊？
No.
不
No!
不要!
Mr. Crocodile,
鱷魚先生
do you like codfish?
你最喜歡船長的肉了
- you do? - oh, Peter, no.
對不對？ 彼得，不要
Smee!
史密!不要怕，船長
Don't go away, cap'n. Stay right there.
你待在那裡啊
I'll save you, sir.
我馬上來救你了
Smee!
史密
Ow!
Cap'n? Cap'n?
船長、船長…
Smee? Smee!
史密!史密!
Give him back!
把船長還給我 史密、史密
Row for the ship. Row for the ship!
快點劃啊，快點劃啊 快劃啊
Whoa!
Smee?
史密，史密…
What about tiger lily?
彼得，莉莉公主怎麼辦？
Tiger lily? Oh, tiger lily.
莉莉公主？ 噢!莉莉公主
Hel...
救…
Peter, wait for me.
彼得，等等我啊
That cursed Peter Pan,
該死的彼得潘
making a fool out of me.
他居然敢這樣捉… 捉弄我…
A- ch... A-chh...
A- choo!
Oh,
my head.
噢!我的頭
Oh, a pirate's life is a wonderful life
哦!海盜的生活是多麼快活
your hot water, Mr. Smee. Shhh!
史密先生，你的熱水 噓…
The poor cap'n has a splitting headache.
可憐的船長像是被撕裂一樣
We mustn't annoy him.
我們不要吵到他
Well, cap'n,
哦!船長
it's nice to see you smiling again.
真高興能再度看到你的笑容啊
Brings backthe good old days..
想起當初
When we was leadin' a healthy, normal life;
我們那些 了不起輝煌日子
Scuttlin' ships, cutting throats.
鑿沉沉船 割斷人的咽喉
Why don't we put to sea again?
船長，為什麼你不再 重操舊業呢？
You know, there's trouble brewing on the island,
你知道嗎？ 小島上隱藏許多的問題啊
women trouble.
女人的問題
I wouldn't want this to go any farther,
我並不想讓它再持續下去
but the cooktold me that the first mate told him...
但是… 廚子他今兒個告訴我
That he heard...
他聽到外面有人在說
That pan has banished Tinkerbell.
彼得潘將小叮噹趕走了
Whoa-ho-ho-ho-ho.
Why, you doddering imbecile, I...
你這個大白癡，我非要…
Did you say...
你是說小叮噹
Pan has banished Tinkerbell?
被彼得潘給趕走了？
Aye, that he has.
嗯…是的
Why?
，船長 好像是…
On account of Wendy. Tinktried to do her in.
為什麼呢？ 好像是溫蒂，船長
Tink's terrible jealous.
小叮噹捉弄了她 小叮噹在吃醋啊
Well, well!
好，很好
That's whywe ought to leave, cap'n.
這就是我們非離開的原因了
This ain't me. No place for a respectable pirate!
我就不信沒有一個地方能 容得下我們這些被尊敬的海盜
That's it, Smee! That's it!
這就對了，這就對了
I'm glad you agrees, cap'n.
嗯？船長？ 很高興你也同意
Quick, my best dress coat.
快點，我的外套 我最好的外套
Aye... Sir, the sooner we gets going, the better.
是，船長 我們越快離開越好啊
Yes, a jealous female can be tricked into anything.
我們可以利用一個 吃醋的女人做出任何的事情
My case of hooks! Aye, aye, sir.
鐵鉤的盒子 是的，船長
Here, sir, your sunday set.
嗯…在這裡啊 你星星期天用的，船長
If we convince the pixie that we're eager to help her,
假如我們設法讓小叮噹相信 我們很想幫助她
the wench may chart our course...
那麼我想她也許會
To a certain hiding place.
肯把他藏身的地方 告訴我們
The spanish main, sir. I'll set our course
藏身的地方在西班牙 船長，我來設定航程啊
and where do you think...
能不能告訴我
You are going?
你現在要去哪裡啊？
To tell the boys we sail with the tide.
船長，我是想去告訴大夥兒
You will go ashore,
我們要出海囉!
pick up Tinkerbell,
你現在要上岸去 找到小叮噹之後呢
and bring her to me.
帶她來見我
Understand?
明白了沒有？
Aye, aye, sir.
嗯…劃，劃
How.
噢!
What's the chief doing, John?
酋長在做什麼啊？約翰
He's delivering an oration...
他在用手勢…
In sign language.
發表演說
What's he saying?
他說什麼啊？
He says, "Peter Pan,
他說彼得潘…
"mightywarrior"
偉大的勇士
save tiger lily.
救出了莉莉公主
Make big chief heap glad."
讓大酋長大大的高興
well, he certainly doesn't look heap glad.
可是他看起來一點也不像 大大的高興喔
Make Peter Pan heap big chief.
大酋長要彼得潘
You now little flying eagle.
你現在是小飛鷹
- hurray for flying eagle. - hurray!
耶!小飛鷹…耶!小飛鷹萬歲!
Oh, howwonderful!
實在是太棒了!
Teach 'em paleface brother all about red man.
把我們紅人的文化傳授給他們
Good. This should be most enlightening.
很好，這樣子是最文明的了
What makes the red man red?
哦…紅人為什麼是紅色的？
When did he first say "ugh"?
他們什麼時候開始會說噢？ 開始會說噢？
Why does he askyou "how"?
他為什麼每次都說噢？
"why does he askyou how?"
我為什麼每次都說噢？
hana mana ganda why does he askyou "how"
為什麼要問你
once the injun didn't knowall things that he know now
當初什麼都不懂 如今他已經學會
but the injun he soon learn a lot
那麼今天他懂了許多
and it's all from asking "how"
卻使他願意發問
hana mana ganda
we translate for you
讓我告訴你
hana means what mana means and ganda means that too
番仔就是番仔 每個番仔都一樣
hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
squaw no dance!
噢!不跳舞
Squaw get 'em firewood.
噢!去撿柴火
Hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
when did he first say "ugh"
何時開始說噢
when did he first say "how"
in the injun book it say
when first brave married squaw
當第一次看到她 她雙眼看著他
he gave out with the heap big "ugh"
令他驚惶失措 而心中忐忑不安
when he saw his mother-in-law
hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
what made the red man red
怎麼是紅的臉
let's go backa million years
這是幾萬年以來
to the very first injun prince
祖先傳下來的傳統
he kiss a maid and start to blush
看我們這樣的打扮
and we all been blushing since
就是我們的傳統
you got it right from the headman
不管故事怎麼記載
the real true story of the red man
也不管變得怎麼記載
no matter what's been written or said
那羽毛還是往頭上戴
nowyou knowwhythe red man's red
我們永遠都是…紅人
wha-hoo!
John?
約翰
Squaw, take 'em papoose.
幫我拿一下好嗎？
Wha-hoo!
Michael?
麥克!
Squaw, get 'em firewood.
噢!去撿柴火
Squaw no get 'em firewood!
我不撿柴火
Squaw go home.
我回家
Beggin' your pardon, miss bell,
對不起啊，小叮噹小姐
but cap'n hookwould like a word with you.
虎克船長想要跟你談一談
Yes, miss bell, Captain Hookadmits defeat.
沒錯，小叮噹小姐 虎克船長承認失敗了
Tomorrow I leave the island...
明天呢，我就會離開小島
Never to return.
永遠也不回來
I'm glad here, cap'n. I'll tell the crew and...
很高興你能同意這一點 我要去告訴船員
And that's why I asked you over, m'dear.
這就是為什麼 我要請你過來，親愛的
To tell Peter I bear him no ill will.
請你轉告彼得 我再也不會恨他了
Oh, pan has his faults, to be sure,
噢，他實在不應該 隨隨便便的呢
bringing that Wendyto the island, for instance.
就把溫蒂 帶到這個小島上來的
Dangerous business, that.
這麼做是不對的
Rumor has it, that already...
嗯…已經有謠言說
She has come between you and Peter.
溫蒂夾在你跟彼得之間 是不是啊？
What's this?
你怎麼了？
Tears?
眼淚？
Then it is true.
那麼說是真的囉？
Oh, Smee,
喔，史密
the way of a man with a maid.
他真是個負心漢啊
Taking the best years of her life and then...
這個女人給了他 一生最美好的青春
Casting her aside...
沒想到他居然把她當成一個
Like an old glove!
不用的舊手套
Ain't it a bloomin' shame?
真是應該慚…愧哎
We mustn't judge Peter too harshly, m'dear.
我們也不能對彼得太苛求了 親愛的
It's that Wendywho's to blame.
都是那個溫蒂惹的禍
Mr. Smee, we must save the lad from himself.
史密先生，我們得想辦法 救救那個孩子
But how?
可是該怎麼做呢？
We've so little time. We sail in the morning.
時間太少了 我們一早就要啟程了
Sail! That's it, Smee.
啟程？ 有了，史密
We'll shanghal Wendy.
我們把溫蒂帶走
Shanghal Wendy, cap'n?
帶溫蒂走？船長？
Take her to sea with us. With her gone,
帶她跟我們一起出海
Peter will forget this infatuation.
只要她一走，彼得很快 就會忘記對她的迷戀
Come, Smee, we must leave, surround Peter's home...
來吧，史密，我們必須 馬上出發，包圍彼得的家
But cap'n,
可…可是，船長
we don't knowwhere Peter Pan lives.
我們不知道 彼得住在哪裡啊
Great scot, you're right!
對啊，你說得一點兒都沒錯
What's that?
你想說什麼？
My dear?
親愛的
You could show us the way?
你要告訴我們地點？
Why, I never thought of that.
唉喲，我怎麼從來就沒有想到呢!
Take this down, Smee.
快把紙筆準備好，史密
"take this down, Smee."
把紙筆準備好，史密
aye, aye, cap'n.
是的，船長
Start at pegleg point.
從木柱角點
Pegleg point.
40-paces left to blindman's bluff.
離盲人斷崖西方40步
Blindman's bluff.
盲人斷崖
Yes, yes.
對了，對了
Hop, skip, and a jump across crocodile creek,
一定要跳過鱷魚溪
then nor' by nor' east, one, two, three.
經過鱷魚溪 然後轉東，一、二、三
Get on with...! Continue my dear.
快一點啊! 喔，親愛的，請繼續
I mustn't harm Peter?
我不可以去傷害彼得？
Madam, Captain Hook gives his word...
哎喲，小姐 我虎克船長在這裡發誓
Not to laya finger...
絕對不會用手指頭
Or a hook on Peter Pan.
呃…鉤子，去傷害彼得
Ah, hangman's tree.
啊哈，吊人樹
So that's the entrance to his hiding place.
原來他就是躲在這個地方啊
Thankyou, m'dear.
謝謝你了，小白癡
You've been most helpful.
你可是幫了大忙了
Hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
hana mana ganda
what makes the red man red
hana mana ganda hana mana ganda
big chief flying eagle greets his braves.
向大酋長飛鷹歡呼
How!
噢!
- how. - how, chief, how.
噢! 酋長，噢!
How. How.
Big chief greets little mother.
噢! 大酋長向小媽媽歡呼
How!
噢!
Ugh.
Wendy, is that all you have to say?
哎，溫蒂 難道你不能大聲點嗎？
They think I'm wonderful.
每個小孩都認為我了不起耶
- especiallytiger lily. - tiger lily?
尤其是莉莉公主，莉莉公主？
John, Michael,
約翰，麥克
take off that war paint and get ready for bed. Bed?
把玩具收一收上床睡覺囉。上床？
Brave no sleep.
勇士不睡覺
Go for days without sleep.
我也決定不要睡覺
We're going home in the morning.
可是我們明天就要回家啦 回家？
Wendy, we don't want to go home.
而且… 溫蒂，你也不想回家吧
No go home.
不要回家，
Stay many moons. Have heap big time.
多住幾天 享受快樂時光
Stop pretending and be practical.
彼得，拜託! 不要再胡鬧了，實際一點嘛
Chief flying eagle has spoken.
飛鷹酋長的話已經說完了
For goodness sake. Please, boys,
噢，我的天啊 難道說…
do you want to stay here and grow up like savages?
你們願意留在這裡 像…像野孩子一樣長大嗎？
'course. You can't. Won't you care you need a mother.
當然囉 不行的，因為你需要媽媽
We all do.
我們都需要
Aren't you our mother, Wendy?
你不是我們的媽媽嗎？溫蒂？
Michael, of course not.
麥克，當然不是囉
Surelyyou haven't forgotten our real mother?
你該不會真的把 我們的媽媽忘記了吧
Did she have silky ears,
她是不是有長長的耳朵
and wear a fur coat?
穿毛毛的大衣
Oh, no, Michael.
天哪，麥克
That was Nana.
那是娜娜
I think I had a mother once.
我好像以前也有媽媽
What was she like?
她像什麼？ 她像什麼？
I forget.
嗯，我忘了
I had a white rat.
我有過一隻白鼠
That's no mother!
那不是媽媽，你打我幹嘛？
No, boys.
我打死你，打死你…
Please. I'll tell you what a mother is.
別鬧了，別鬧了 好了，孩子們
- tell us. Tell us. - please, Wendy.
我來告訴你們媽媽像什麼，告訴我們，快說嘛…快嘛
A mother, a real mother,
嗯，媽媽 真正的媽媽
is the most wonderful person in the world.
她是世界上最好的人
She's the angel voice...
她有天使般的聲音
That bids you good night,
送你上床睡覺
kisses your cheek,
親吻你的臉
whispers, "sleep tight."
還幫你把被被蓋好
your motherand mine
溫柔好媽媽
the helping hand
有著照顧你的一雙手
that guides you along
不論是對
whether you're right，whether you're wrong
不論是錯
your motherand mine
溫柔好媽媽
溫柔……好媽媽
what makes mothers
是什麼讓母親的愛
all that they are
如同
might as well ask
星星星星
what makes a star
光耀燦爛
askyour heart
誰能
to tell you her worth
懷疑母親的愛
your heart will say
心中明白
heaven on earth
眼上的笑
another word
沒有話…
for divine
可以形容…
your motherand mine.
你母親的愛
I wanna see my mother.
我要回去找媽媽
Yes, Michael.
好的，麥克
I propose we leave for home at once.
我建議我們現在就回家
- could I go too, Wendy? - me too, Wendy.
溫蒂，我也可以去嗎？我也可以去嗎？ 我也要去好不好？
All right, boys.
好好好，沒問題
I'm sure mother would be glad to have you.
我想我母親 會很高興接納你們的
That is, if Peter doesn't mind.
但是…只要…彼得他肯答應
Go on go backand grow up. But I'm warnin' you,
去啊，回去長大啊
once you're grown up, you can never come back.
可是我警告你們，只要你們長大 就永遠回不來了
Never!
永遠!
Dear.
兄弟們，
Shall we be off?
我們走吧
- come on, let's go. - we'll have lots of fun.
走囉，我們走吧…
They'll be back.
他們會回來的
Peter?
彼得…
Goodbye, Peter.
再見，彼得
All right men, take them away!
快，把他們帶走
And now, Smee,
好了，史密
to take care of master Peter Pan.
現在我們可以收拾彼得潘了
Cap'n, wouldn't it be more... Humane-like...
可是，船長，我們能不能
To slit his throat?
更人性一點來解決這件事呢？
Aye, that it would, Mr. Smee,
當然可以啦，史密
but I have given me word...
但是我保證過
Not to laya finger or a hook...
絕對不用手指頭或者是鉤子
On Peter Pan.
去傷害彼得潘
And capt. Hook...
我虎克船長
Never breaks a promise.
絕對不會食言的
Yo-ho, yo-ho, yoho-yoho-yoho
喲喝，喲喝 喲喝，喲喝，喲喝
so trythe life of a thief
海盜是我的一生
just sample the life of a crook
也喜歡到處欺騙人
there isn't a boywho won't enjoy
來加入我們行業
a- workin' for capt. Hook
保證不會浪費這一生
the world's most famous crook
別浪費這一生
crook, crook, crickety, crockety
crickety crick
the croc is after capt...
別浪費這一生
A special offer for today.
今天有好消息
I'll tell you what I'll do
我要向大家來宣佈
all those who sign without delay
不要猶豫，動作要快
will get a free tattoo
一份勝利禮物
for it's like money in the bank
好好努力，就趁現在
come on, join up, and I'll be frank
來吧，加入我的腳步
unless you do
趕快加入，
you'll walkthe plank
否則跳海
the choice is up to you
你自己下賭注
yo-ho, yo-ho, yo-ho
喲喝，喲喝 喲喝
yoho-yoho-yoho
，喲喝，喲喝
you'll love the life of a thief
海盜是我的一生
you'll relish the life of a crook
也喜歡到處欺騙人
there's barrels of fun for everyone
來加入我們行業
and you'll get treasures bythe ton
保證你不會浪費了這一生
so come and sign the book
該不用再考慮
join up with capt. Hook
虎克船長在這，快點… 我們趕快去簽啊…
boys!
孩子們
Aren't you ashamed of yourselves?
你們不覺得丟人嗎？
But capt. Hook is most insistent, Wendy.
可是虎克船長他非常堅持啊 溫蒂
Yeah, or we'll walkthe plank!
對啊，假如我們不簽 就要走上跳板耶
No, we won't.
不，不會的
Peter Pan will save us.
彼得潘會來救我們的
Peter Pan will save them.
彼得潘會來救他們 哈…哈
Peter Pan will save them!
彼得潘會來救他們
Oh, cap'n.
笑死我了，船長
A thousand pardons, my dear.
千萬個對不起啊，親愛的
I don't believe you are in on our little joke.
我真不敢相信你掉進 我們的小陷阱了
You see, we left a present for Peter.
老實說呢 我們留給彼得潘一點兒小禮物
Sort of a surprise package, you might say.
一個會讓他感到意外的包裹
Why, I can see our little friend at this moment,
喔…我已經看到我們那個 可愛的小朋友
reading the tender inscription.
在看那上面的小卡片了
"to Peter, with love from Wendy.
給彼得 愛你的溫蒂
Do not open till 6 o'clock."
六點以前不准打開
huh?
I wonder what's in it?
怪了，什麼啊？
Could he but see within the package,
他是不會知道裡面是什麼的
he would find an ingenious little device.
如果他打開了他將會看到一個精緻的儀器
Set so when the clock is like this,
時間已設定好，等它… 變成這樣
Peter Pan...
彼得潘
Will be blasted out of neverland...
將會被炸得
Forever.
永遠都回不到這個…夢幻島了
No!
不…
But, time grows short.
時間所剩不多了
We have but...
我們還有
18 seconds.
大概18秒…
15 seconds.
15秒…
13 seconds.
13秒…
12 seconds.
12秒…
I guess I could open it now.
我想我可以打開了
Hi, tink. Lookwhat Wendy left.
嘿，小叮噹 你看，溫蒂送我的
Hey, stop that!
哎，住手
Stop it. What's the matter with you?
哎，住手 幹什麼嘛你？
A bomb?
虎克？炸彈？
Don't be ridiculous.
別開玩笑了
So passeth a worthy opponent.
再見了!可憐的對手
Amen.
阿門!
Hook! It was a bomb.
虎克!真的是一枚炸彈
If it hadn't been for tink...
假如不是小叮噹的話 小叮噹!
Tinkerbell?
小叮噹？
Tink? Tinkerbell?
小叮噹？小叮噹…
Where are you, tink?
你在哪裡啊？
Tink? Tinkerbell!
小叮噹？ 小叮噹
Tink?
小叮噹，你沒事吧？
Wendy ? The boys?
溫蒂？孩子們？
But I've got to save you first!
可是我得先救你啊
Hold on, tink.
撐著點!小叮噹，
Ting-a... Don't go out.
撐著點哦!
Don't you understand?
小叮噹，你知道嗎？
You mean more to me than anything in this whole world!
在這個世界上 你是我最親的人了
And now, which will it be?
呃，現在你們選擇是什麼呢？
The pen... Or the plank?
是筆？還是跳板？
Capt. Hook, we will never join your crew.
虎克船長 我們永遠不會加入你們的
As you wish. Ladies first, m'dear.
隨你的便 女士優先，請吧!
Goodbye, boys. Goodbye, Wendy.
再見了，孩子們 再見，溫蒂
Be brave, John. I shall strive to, Wendy.
約翰，勇敢一點 我不會退縮的，溫蒂
Goodbye, Michael. Goodbye.
麥克，再見了 再見
Come on! Go on with ya!
你過來，走開
Go on, go on! Get it over with!
把那個孩子帶過來 上去!快上去!
Move along!
快點，不要拖拖拉拉的 趕快跳下去，往前走!
快跳海… 快跳啊…吵什麼？
Wendy! Wendy!
溫蒂，溫蒂…
Cap'n, no splash.
船…船長，沒有水聲啊
Not a sound.
一點聲音也沒有
- not a bloomin' ripple. - it's a jinx, that's what.
沒有濺水的聲音不祥之人 她是個不祥之人哎
- no splash. - no sign of the wench.
還有沒有跳水聲耶 看不到那個女孩在哪兒
- did you hear a splash? - I'm tellin' you mates,
你有沒有聽到 水濺起來的聲音啊？
it's a black day. Mark me words.
沒有啊，好可怕呀
We'll all pay for this.
怎麼會這樣呢？ 好恐怖
The ship's bewitched.
這條船著魔了
No... Splash, cap'n.
沒有聽到聲音呢，船長
So, you want a splash, Mr. Starkey?
怎麼？你要跳水聲 是不是啊？史達克
I'll give you a splash!
那我就給你一個跳水聲
Who's next? You're next, hook!
誰是下一個？ 下一個就是你
This time you've gone too far!
這一次你實在太過份了
It's pan. It's pan!
是彼得潘
- and Wendy. - it can't be.
對啊!還有溫蒂 不可能的
It's his blinkin' ghost talking.
是他的鬼魂在說話
Sayyour prayers, hook!
I'll showyou this ghost...
我可以肯定
Has blood in his veins!
這隻鬼的血管裡有血!
I'll run him through!
我一定要抓到他
Ooo-oooo!
Take that!
去死吧!
Curse this hook!
這個爛鐵鉤
Come on, everybody!
孩子們，快走!
Hurry, Michael.
快點，麥克，快啊!
Don't stand there, you bilge rats.
你們不要愣在那兒啊
Get those scurvy brats!
趕快去捉那些小混蛋
After the brats!
這下你跑不掉了吧…
This is no mere boy. 'tis some fiend fighting me.
已經不是一個小孩子跟我鬥了
A flying devil!
是一個會飛的惡魔
Hold your fire.
先別急喔
Steady, men, steady.
兄弟們，穩住
Grab 'em!
臭小鬼
Fire!
開火
Down, you blackguard!
你這壞蛋，下去!
Ha-ha.
快啊!快啊!跑不掉的，你…
Hurray!
好棒、好棒…
Well done, Michael!
你真行，麥克 麥克，你好棒喔!
Hurray for bear killer!
麥克，你好勇敢喔!
Fly, fly, fly, you coward!
飛，飛，飛 你這個懦夫
Coward? Me?
懦夫？我？
Ha-ha-ha! You wouldn't dare...
哈!哈!哈!我就知道你不敢
Fight old hook man-to-man.
面對面的跟我虎克打
You'd flyaway like a cowardly sparrow!
你一定會像個懦夫一樣的飛走
Nobody calls pan a coward and lives!
沒有人敢叫彼得潘是懦夫
I'll fight you man to man with one hand behind my back.
我就跟你面對面打 而且還把一隻手擺在背後
You mean, you won't fly?
你是說你不會飛了？
No, Peter, it's a trick!
不，不要，彼得，他耍詐
I give my word. Good!
我向你保證，
Then let's have at it!
虎克 好，一言為定
Now!
啊哈!
Insolent youth, prepare to die!
你這個不知死活的小子 準備受死吧
Fly, Peter. Fly!
飛啊、飛啊…彼得，飛啊
No! I gave myword.
不，我保證過了
You're mine!
你完蛋了，虎克
Cleave him to the brisket!
把他砍成兩半
You wouldn't do old hook in now would you, lad?
你不會把老虎克怎麼樣的吧 對不對啊？
I'll go away forever.
我會永遠離開這裡的
I'll do anything you say!
我什麼都會聽你的
Well, all right, if you sayyou're a codfish!
那…好吧! 你說…你是個膽小鬼
I'm a codfish.
我是個膽小鬼
Louder!
大聲一點
I'm a codfish!
我是個膽小鬼
Hurray!
耶!
Hook is a codfish, a codfish
虎克膽小鬼，膽小鬼，膽小鬼
a codfish, hook is a codfish
虎克膽小鬼…
all right, hook, you're free to go,
好了，虎克你可以走了
and never...
而且永遠不准回來
Return.Peter!
彼得，小心!
噢…!
Smee? Sme...
史密!史密!
Smee?
史密!
史密!史密!
Smee!
史密…
Cap'n?
哎…船長
Cap'n? Cap'n!
船長，等等我們啊 不要走那麼快
Hurray!
喔耶!
Hurray for captain pan!
喔耶!彼得船長，萬歲! 萬歲!
All right, you swabs,
好了，大家安靜，趕快收拾
aloft with ya! We're castin' off!
我們要準備啟航了
Heave those halyards!
把帆拉起來
But pe?? R, that is, captain pan...
可…可是，彼得… 噢…我是說船長大人
At your service.
小姐有何吩咐？
Could you tell me, sir, where we're sailing?
你能不能告訴我 我們要去哪裡？
To London, madam.
去倫敦啊
Oh, Peter.
噢…彼得
Michael? John? We're going home.
約翰、麥克 我們要回家了
Man the capstan!
水手們起錨!
Hoist anchor!
拉起後錨!
Pixie dust!
灑金粉!
George, I'm so glad...
喬治，我真高興
After all, you changed your mind about Wendy.
你對溫蒂的看法改變了
She's still a child.
再怎麼說她還是個孩子嘛
Mary, you know I never mean those things.
哎喲，瑪莉，你知道 我對孩子從來就沒有認真過嘛
Do I, Nana?
對不對？娜娜
Oh!
噢
Wendy?
溫蒂
Wendy, what on earth are you doing there?
溫蒂，你在這裡做什麼？
Hmm?
Oh mother, we're back!
啊!媽媽，我回來啦
Back?
回來？
Except the lost boys. Theyweren't ready.
除了那些迷失的小孩 他們還沒有準備好
Lost bo...? Ready? To grow up.
迷失的小孩？準備好？ 長大啊!
That's why they went back to neverland. Neverland?
所以才又回到夢幻島去了。夢幻島？
Yes, but, I am.
是的…可是我已經…
Uh, am?
怎麼樣啊？
Readyto grow up.
準備長大了
Oh, oh!
噢…
Well wish, my dear, all in good time.
親愛的，人總會長大的嘛，每個人都會有一段美好的
After all, perhaps we were... But mother,
成長過程啊對不對？ 可是，媽媽…
it was such a wonderful adventure,
那是一次好棒的冒險耶!
Tinkerbell, and the mermaids,
小叮噹、美人魚
and Peter Pan! He was the most wonderful of all!
還有彼得潘！噢，他是最棒的 甚至，甚至…
When kidnapp...
當我們被綁架的時候
Kidnapped?
被綁架？
Uh-hmm. I knew Peter Pan...
嗯哼!我就知道彼得
Would save us, and he did.
會來救我的，他真的來了耶
We all called him a codfish!
我們都叫他膽小鬼
Captain Hook, I mean.
我是說虎克船長啦
And then...
藉著
We sailed away on a ship in the sky.
當我們坐船飛過天空
Ah, mary, I'm going to bed.
我想我還是去睡覺好了
Oh, mother,
噢，媽…
he really is wonderful, isn't he?
他真的好棒對不對？
See howwell he sails the ship.
你看，他船開得多好啊
George? George!
喬治，喬治
Nowwhat, mary?
哎，又幹什麼？瑪莉啊？
Who?
誰？
Nana, did you see...
娜娜，你看見了沒有？
You know, I have the strangest feeling...
你知道嗎？ 我有一種好奇怪的感覺啊
That I've seen that ship before,
我好像見過那艘船耶
a long time ago...
在很久很久以前
When I was very young.
那時候我還很小…
George, dear.
喬治
Father.
爸！
When there's a smile in your heart
there's no better time to start
think of all the joy you'll find
when you leave the world behind
and bid your cares goodbye
you can fly
over
(謝謝觀賞)